[
    {
        "question": "Arrange the words given below in a meaningful sequence. 1. Word 2. Paragraph 3. Sentence 4. Letters 5. Phrase",
        "options": [
            "4, 1, 5, 2, 3",
            "4, 1, 3, 5, 2",
            "4, 2, 5, 1, 3",
            "4, 1, 5, 3, 2"
        ],
        "answer": "4, 1, 5, 3, 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arrange the words given below in a meaningful sequence. 1. Police 2. Punishment 3. Crime 4. Judge 5. Judgement",
        "options": [
            "3, 1, 2, 4, 5",
            "1, 2, 4, 3, 5",
            "5, 4, 3, 2, 1",
            "3, 1, 4, 5, 2"
        ],
        "answer": "3, 1, 4, 5, 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arrange the words given below in a meaningful sequence. 1. Protect 2. Pressure 3. Relief 4. Rain 5. Flood",
        "options": [
            "2, 4, 3, 1, 5",
            "2, 4, 5, 1, 3",
            "2, 5, 4, 1, 3",
            "3, 2, 4, 5, 1"
        ],
        "answer": "2, 4, 5, 1, 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arrange the words given below in a meaningful sequence. 1. Presentation 2. Recommendation 3. Arrival 4. Discussion 5. Introduction",
        "options": [
            "5, 3, 4, 1, 2",
            "3, 5, 4, 2, 1",
            "3, 5, 1, 4, 2",
            "5, 3, 1, 2, 4"
        ],
        "answer": "3, 5, 1, 4, 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the sentence with the correct grammatical structure:",
        "options": [
            "If I had known this yesterday I will have helped him.",
            "If I had known this yesterday I would have helped him.",
            "If I had known this yesterday I will help him.",
            "If I had known this yesterday I would help him."
        ],
        "answer": "If I had known this yesterday I would have helped him."
    },
    {
        "question": "I could not put up in a hotel because the boarding and lodging charges were exorbitant. Identify the part with the error.",
        "options": [
            "I could not put up in a hotel",
            "because the boarding and lodging charges",
            "were exorbitant.",
            "No error."
        ],
        "answer": "I could not put up at a hotel"
    },
    {
        "question":"Choose the incorrectly spelt word among all the given options.",
        "options": [
            "Acquaintance",
            "Maneouvre",
            "Erroneously",
            "Demurrage"
        ],
        "answer": "Maneouvre"
    },
    {
        "question":"Choose the incorrectly spelt word among all the given options.",
        "options":[
            "Strategy",
            "Strenth",
            "Strictly",
            "Stretch"
        ],
        "answer":"Strenth"
    },
    {
        "question": "When he P : did not know Q : he was nervous and R : heard the hue and cry at midnight S : what to do. The Proper sequence should be:",
        "options": [
            "RQPS",
            "QSPR",
            "SQPR",
            "PQRS"
        ],
        "answer": "RQPS"
    },
    {
        "question": "It has been established that P : Einstein was Q : although a great scientist R : weak in arithmetic S : right from his school days. The Proper sequence should be:",
        "options": [
            "SRPQ",
            "QPRS",
            "QPSR",
            "RQPS"
        ],
        "answer": "SRPQ"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then P : it struck me Q : of course R : suitable it was S : how eminently. The Proper sequence should be:",
        "options": [
            "SPQR",
            "QSRP",
            "PSRQ",
            "QPSR"
        ],
        "answer": "SPQR"
    },
    {
        "question": "After driving professor Kumar to the museum she dropped him at his hotel. What is its passive voice?",
        "options": [
            "After being driven to the museum, Professor Kumar was dropped at his hotel.",
            "Professor Kumar was being driven dropped at his hotel.",
            "After she had driven Professor Kumar to the museum she had dropped him at his hotel.",
            "After she was driven Professor Kumar to the museum she had dropped him at his hotel."
        ],
        "answer": "After being driven to the museum, Professor Kumar was dropped at his hotel."
    },
    {
        "question": "I remember my sister taking me to the museum. What is its passive voice?",
        "options": [
            "I remember I was taken to the museum by my sister.",
            "I remember being taken to the museum by my sister.",
            "I remember myself being taken to the museum by my sister.",
            "I remember taken to the museum by my sister."
        ],
        "answer": "I remember being taken to the museum by my sister."
    },
    {
        "question": "They greet me cheerfully every morning. What is its passive voice?",
        "options": [
            "Every morning I was greeted cheerfully.",
            "I am greeted cheerfully by them every morning.",
            "I am being greeted cheerfully by them every morning.",
            "Cheerful greeting is done by them every morning to me."
        ],
        "answer": "I am greeted cheerfully by them every morning."
    },
    {
        "question": "Darjeeling grows tea. What is its passive voice?",
        "options": [
            "Tea is being grown in Darjeeling.",
            "Let the tea be grown in Darjeeling.",
            "Tea is grown in Darjeeling.",
            "Tea grows in Darjeeling."
        ],
        "answer": "Tea is grown in Darjeeling."
    },
    {
        "question": "If you don't keep quiet I shall shoot you, he said to her in a calm voice. Choose the corresponding indirect speech.",
        "options": [
            "He warned her to shoot if she didn't keep quiet calmly.",
            "He said calmly that I shall shoot you if you don't be quiet.",
            "He warned her calmly that he would shoot her if she didn't keep quiet.",
            "Calmly he warned her that be quiet or else he will have to shoot her."
        ],
        "answer": "He warned her calmly that he would shoot her if she didn't keep quiet."
    },
    {
        "question": "I told him that he was not working hard. Pick the appropriate direct sentence.",
        "options": [
            "I said to him, You are not working hard.",
            "I told to him, You are not working hard.",
            "I said, You are not working hard.",
            "I said to him, He is not working hard."
        ],
        "answer": "I said to him, You are not working hard."
    },
    {
        "question": "His father ordered him to go to his room and study. Choose the corresponding direct speech.",
        "options": [
            "His father said, Go to your room and study.",
            "His father said to him, Go and study in your room.",
            "His father shouted, Go right now to your study room.",
            "His father said firmly, Go and study in your room."
        ],
        "answer": "His father said, Go to your room and study."
    }
]